### **Russell Smith**

Phone : (+353) 83 899 3922 Email: <u>russellsmith83@gmail.com</u> Site: <u>russ-smith.github.io</u> LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/russell-smith-52335a103</u> GitHub: <u>github.com/russ-smith</u>

#### About

I'm a software developer with 3.5 years' post-grad experience. I've worked on games and related projects in Shanghai (a mostly graphics-focused role) and Dublin (a more all-round position involving both client and server development, and release management). I'm a keen coder for fun as well as for work, and I thrive on solving interesting and difficult challenges, and collaborating with art and design teams at the intersection between technical and creative work.

# Industry experience

Zulleon Ltd.

Dublin http://zulleon.com/

**Software Engineer** – March 2019 - present

Part of a small team of developers and artists creating games, animated shorts and interactive stories for kids. Working mostly with C# and Unity for game client code, and Ruby on Rails and Javascript for backend development.

- Debugged and optimised issues in our pre-existing app, What's That Rumbling
- Worked with the team to design, code, test, launch and maintain a collection of kids' games featuring our OOKs characters, which shipped in late 2019
- Upgraded our backend payment system to handle foreign currency payments and SCA.
- Identified and fixed data integrity issues on our live server

## 上海龙玩网络科技有限公司 (Shanghai Dragon Play)

Hongkou, Shanghai <a href="https://ckfksc.com/">https://ckfksc.com/</a>

Unity Developer - March 2016–March 2018

Graphics and gameplay programming for a recently-formed 'AA' indie studio making multiplayer mobile-first FTP games for Chinese and other Asian markets. Working mostly in C# and Cq/Shaderlab, with a bit of C++ and Javascript.

- Worked with the art team to implement in-game and UI FX, and develop custom model and environment shaders.
- Debugged graphics issues on various devices.
- Built a prototype educational app for VR as sole developer, taking it from a design spec to a working demo.
- Ported a game audio system from FMOD to native Unity for a web deployment and implemented music streaming from server.

Examples of projects I worked on can be found at russ-smith.github.io/work

### Related experience

鹿谷教育(Hi-Loogoos Science Camp)

Pudong, Shanghai

Programming instructor - September 2017-July 2018

Weekend and summer holiday lessons teaching 10-16 year olds the fundamentals of programming using Python. In addition to teaching, I collaborated with other teachers to design the curriculum for each class, and create small applications and games to serve as class projects.

# **Education**

**B.Sc. Creative Computing** - First class honours (85%) University of London (distance learning) – 2016

Modules covered – Maths for computing, OO programming, architecture, software engineering, algorithm design and analysis, security and encryption, compression, databases, UX design, audio and graphics programming.

Final project – Modelling 3D Fractals on GPU using modern OpenGL

# Skills

# Languages and APIs

C#, C++, Python, Ruby, GLSL, HLSL/Cg, OpenGL, Unity API, Rails

#### Tools

Unity Editor, Git, SVN, Visual Studio, Audacity, GIMP, Linux